[
    {
        "question": "Leen usually ............ the 8 o'clock train to work.",
        "choices": [
            "has caught",
            "is catching",
            "catch",
            "catches"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "catches"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aya ............ late for work.",
        "choices": [
            "never is",
            "is never",
            "never has",
            "has never"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is never"
    },
    {
        "question": "When ............ you usually finish studying your lessons?",
        "choices": [
            "are",
            "have",
            "do",
            "does"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "does"
    },
    {
        "question": "Omar ............ come to work late at all.",
        "choices": [
            "never",
            "doesn't",
            "don't",
            "isn't"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "never"
    },
    {
        "question": "Omar ............ comes to work late.",
        "choices": [
            "never",
            "doesn't",
            "don't",
            "isn't"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "never"
    },
    {
        "question": "I always ............ the piano after I come home from work.",
        "choices": [
            "plays",
            "play",
            "played",
            "playing"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "play"
    },
    {
        "question": "I always ............ the piano after I came home from work.",
        "choices": [
            "plays",
            "play",
            "played",
            "playing"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "played"
    },
    {
        "question": "He usually ............ very quickly, so we didn't understand him.",
        "choices": [
            "speaks",
            "spoke",
            "was spoken",
            "speaking"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "speaks"
    },
    {
        "question": "He usually ............ very quickly, so we don't understand him.",
        "choices": [
            "speaks",
            "spoke",
            "was spoken",
            "speaking"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "speaking"
    },
    {
        "question": "My friends often came to my birthday party and ............ me nice presents.",
        "choices": [
            "have given",
            "were giving",
            "give",
            "gave"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "gave"
    },
    {
        "question": "My friends often come to my birthday party and ............ me nice presents.",
        "choices": [
            "have given",
            "were giving",
            "give",
            "gave"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "give"
    },
    {
        "question": "When I was on holiday, I ............ tennis every day.",
        "choices": [
            "had played",
            "have played",
            "play",
            "played"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "played"
    },
    {
        "question": "When I am on holiday, I ............ tennis every day.",
        "choices": [
            "had played",
            "have played",
            "play",
            "played"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "play"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sama ............ an email to her friend but she has received no reply so far.",
        "choices": [
            "sends",
            "is sent",
            "sent",
            "was sent"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "sends"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rubbish ............ and burnt.",
        "choices": [
            "are collected",
            "collected",
            "collects",
            "is collected"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is collected"
    },
    {
        "question": "He often ............ with me in English to become better at speaking.",
        "choices": [
            "is speaking",
            "has spoken",
            "spoke",
            "speaks"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "speaks"
    },
    {
        "question": "We ............ an interesting film last night.",
        "choices": [
            "watched",
            "had watched",
            "watch",
            "have watched"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "watched"
    },
    {
        "question": "Policemen ............ criminals and arrest them.",
        "choices": [
            "hunt",
            "hunts",
            "are hunting",
            "hunted"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "hunt"
    },
    {
        "question": "They ............ attend the conference last month.",
        "choices": [
            "wasn't",
            "weren't",
            "didn't",
            "don't"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "weren't"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the timetable, the train ............ at 11 o'clock.",
        "choices": [
            "is arriving",
            "arrives",
            "is going to arrive",
            "had arrived"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "arrives"
    },
    {
        "question": "She ............ the newspaper every morning. It is a habit of hers.",
        "choices": [
            "is reading",
            "has read",
            "read",
            "reads"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "reads"
    },
    {
        "question": "She ............ the newspaper every morning. It was a habit of hers.",
        "choices": [
            "is reading",
            "has read",
            "read",
            "reads"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "read"
    },
    {
        "question": "What time ............ you usually arrive at school when you were a student?",
        "choices": [
            "do",
            "would",
            "did",
            "does"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "did"
    },
    {
        "question": "What time ............ you usually arrive at school when you take a taxi?",
        "choices": [
            "do",
            "would",
            "did",
            "does"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "does"
    },
    {
        "question": "My son ............ ambitious and he wants to study medicine.",
        "choices": [
            "is always",
            "always is",
            "doesn't always",
            "isn't always"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is always"
    },
    {
        "question": "When I finished my work, I closed my office and ............ home.",
        "choices": [
            "return",
            "returning",
            "had returned",
            "returned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "returned"
    },
    {
        "question": "His mother ............ his room door while he was studying his lessons.",
        "choices": [
            "opened",
            "opening",
            "was opening",
            "opens"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "was opening"
    },
    {
        "question": "The moon ............ around the earth.",
        "choices": [
            "has moved",
            "will move",
            "moves",
            "moved"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "moves"
    },
    {
        "question": "He phoned me once he ............ the message.",
        "choices": [
            "had read",
            "will read",
            "reads",
            "read"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "read"
    },
    {
        "question": "He will phone me once he ............ the message.",
        "choices": [
            "had read",
            "will read",
            "has read",
            "read"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "has read"
    },
    {
        "question": "............ I was twelve, my family moved into this flat.",
        "choices": [
            "While",
            "When",
            "During",
            "As"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "When"
    },
    {
        "question": "He ............ early.",
        "choices": [
            "rarely is",
            "is rare",
            "is rarely",
            "rare is"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is rarely"
    },
    {
        "question": "He ............ up early.",
        "choices": [
            "rarely gets",
            "gets rarely",
            "get rarely",
            "rarely get"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "rarely gets"
    },
    {
        "question": "It hardly ............ in Egypt.",
        "choices": [
            "is raining",
            "rains",
            "have rained",
            "raining"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "rains"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a schoolboy, my uncle always ............ to school on foot.",
        "choices": [
            "gone",
            "went",
            "goes",
            "will go"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "went"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mum ............ by all family members.",
        "choices": [
            "is loving",
            "is being loved",
            "is loved",
            "loves"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is loved"
    },
    {
        "question": "I'll phone you as soon as I............ my work.",
        "choices": [
            "finishes",
            "finish",
            "will finish",
            "had finished"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "finishes"
    },
    {
        "question": "We all ............ in Allah .",
        "choices": [
            "believe",
            "believes",
            "is believing",
            "are believing"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "believe"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is time we ............ home .",
        "choices": [
            "went",
            "are going",
            "go",
            "have gone"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "go"
    },
    {
        "question": "............. the email sent before the office was closed?",
        "choices": [
            "Are",
            "Was",
            "Had",
            "Does"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Was"
    },
    {
        "question": "During his last holiday, Tamer ............ football every day.",
        "choices": [
            "is playing",
            "played",
            "plays",
            "has played"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "played"
    },
    {
        "question": "He ............ playing tennis.",
        "choices": [
            "use to",
            "is used to",
            "used to",
            "was used"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "used to"
    },
    {
        "question": "A: Have you seen her lately?",
        "choices": [
            "saw",
            "had seen",
            "have seen",
            "was seeing"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "have seen"
    },
    {
        "question": "All the information I read in this book ............ very valuable and useful.",
        "choices": [
            "is being",
            "has",
            "is",
            "are"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ten people ............ to have been injured in the crash.",
        "choices": [
            "had reported",
            "have reported",
            "were reported",
            "were reporting"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "were reported"
    },
    {
        "question": "Don't open the door until I ............ you.",
        "choices": [
            "told",
            "had told",
            "tell",
            "was told"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "was told"
    },
    {
        "question": "I am sure he ............ a Samsung laptop. He just doesn't want to lend it to you.",
        "choices": [
            "is having",
            "is going to have",
            "will have",
            "has"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "is having"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Salma read a story, she ............ interested in its moral.",
        "choices": [
            "is usually",
            "was usually",
            "usually is",
            "usually was"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "usually is"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"He used to work as a firefighter.\" This means ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "he is a firefighter",
            "he works as a firefighter",
            "he is no longer a firefighter",
            "he never worked as a firefighter"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "he is no longer a firefighter"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I wish I were tall.\" What does this mean?",
        "choices": [
            "I am tall",
            "I am not short",
            "I used to be tall",
            "I am not tall"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "I am not short"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"It is time Omar paid me back my money.\" This means ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "Omar had returned my money",
            "Omar hasn't returned my money",
            "Omar returned my money",
            "Omar has just returned my money"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Omar hasn't returned my money"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I'd rather Sama hadn't used my cream yesterday.\" This means ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "Sama used my cream yesterday",
            "Sama didn't use my cream yesterday",
            "Sama asked to use my cream yesterday",
            "Sama agreed to use my cream yesterday"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Sama didn't use my cream yesterday"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Plants get their food from the sun\". This is a ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "present habit",
            "past habit",
            "future fact",
            "fact"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "fact"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"We take mid-year exams in January\". This is a ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "timetable",
            "future fact",
            "habit",
            "hope"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "timetable"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I don't smoke heavily any longer.\" I mean that I ............ .",
        "choices": [
            "smoke heavily",
            "used to be a heavy smoker",
            "haven't stopped smoking",
            "didn't use to smoke"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "haven't stopped smoking"
    }
]